我曾经认为
I used to think
这是你的故事的开始
this was the beginning of your story.
回忆是一种奇怪的东西
Memory is a strange thing.
因为它和我所想的不太一样
It doesn't work like I thought it did.
我们太局限于时间 因果顺序
We are so bound by time, by its order.
好
Okay.
好 来我这儿
Okay. Come back to me.
让妈妈抱抱
Come back to me.
把手举起来
Stick 'em up!
你就是镇上的警长
Are you the sheriff in this here town?
这是我的挠痒枪 我会抓住你
These are my tickle guns, and I'm gonna getcha!
不
No!
你想让我追你 你最好得跑了
You want me to chase you? You better run!
-啊 -哦
- Ah! - Oh!
我还记得中间的一些片段
I remember moments in the middle.
我爱你
I love you.
我恨你
I hate you!
到这里就结束了
And this was the end.
嘘
Shhh...
到妈妈这里来
Come back to me.
回到妈妈这里
You come back to me.
可现在我不确定
But now I'm not so sure
我还能不能分得清起点和终点了
I believe in beginnings and endings.
有那么一段你生命之外的时间 勾勒出你的故事
There are days that define your story beyond your life.
就像它们降临的那天
Like the day they arrived.
早上好
Good morning.
Morning.
大家都去哪了
Where is everyone?
好吧 那咱们开始上课
Okay. Well, let's get started.
今天我们来讲葡萄牙语
Today we are talking about Portuguese
以及其为什么听起来和
and why it sounds so different
其他的罗马语系那么不同
from the other Romance languages.
葡萄牙语起源于加利西亚王国
The story of Portuguese begins in the kingdom of Galicia...
-抱歉 -在中世纪的时候
- Sorry. - ...in the Middle Ages,
语言被视作为对艺术的一种表达
where language was seen as an expression of art.
有什么想分享的新闻吗
Any news you want to share?
班克斯博士 您能打开电视看新闻台吗
Dr. Banks, can you turn the TV to a news channel?
警察已经在该处周边区域
...but police have already set up a blockade
设置了封锁
here around the area.
如你所见 我们尽了最大可能走近
As you can see, we've got just about as close as we can,
但不幸的是
but unfortunately,
蒙大拿现在是完全封锁的状态
Montana right now is on complete lockdown.
该物体是在40分钟前着陆于
The object apparently touched down 40 minutes ago,
94号州际公路的北侧
just north of I-94.
我们在这里等候消息
We're waiting to hear if this is perhaps
看看这是不是一艘实验飞船或是
an experimental vessel or...
稍等
Hold on, it...
我刚刚得知还有更多像这样的物体
I'm learning that more objects like this have landed in
降落在世界上
as many as eight other locations
多达八个其他的位置
around the world.
是的 我们能
Yes, can we?
这是来自北海道的画面
This is from a site in Hokkaido.
这是正在发生的 全球性事件
This is worldwide. It is happening right now.
好吧 呃
Okay. Um...
抱歉 下课吧
I'm sorry. Class is dismissed.
你个笨蛋 直着往我这开
You are an idiot! You drove right into me!
你把我车都撞坏了
You just ruined my car!
现在 在当局对该物体进行评估时
For now, we're simply asking for cooperation
我们只希望大家能够配合
while authorities assess the object.
那你的意思是说这不是我们国家的
So, you're saying it's not ours?
你知道它是否来自地球吗
Do you even know if it's from Earth?
我们目前还在搜集信息
We 're still collecting information.
还有与其他国家进行协调
We're coordinating with other countries.
我们不是唯一一个在境内出现
We're not the only ones to
这么个东西的国家
have one of these in our backyard.
如果这是某种和平的第一类接触
If this is some sort of peaceful first contact,
为什么发来12个
why send 12?
为什么不就派一艘来
Why not just one?
是啊 我知道 我看到那个了
Yeah, I know. I saw that, too.
嗯
Uh-huh.
嗯 妈我不知道
Uh-huh. I don't know, Mom.
我和您看的是一样的新闻
I'm watching the same news coverage you are.
行了 妈 您别理那些电视台
Well, Mom, please don't bother with that channel.
我跟您说过多少次了 那些人都是笨蛋
How many times do I have to tell you? Those people are idiots.
是啊 行了 我听起来紧张吗
Yeah, well, do I sound nervous?
是 可不嘛
Okay. Exactly. So...
我 是啊 您懂我的
Um, me? Yeah, um, you know me.
还那么回事
I'm about the same.
妈 我挺好的
Mom, I'm fine.
好啦 我会再给您打的 再见
Okay, I'll call you later. Bye.
从降临到现在大约八小时
And around eight hours after landing,
目前还没有任何被称为第一类接触
there are still no signs of what might be called
的迹象
"First contact."
现在 物体至少有一千五百英尺高
Now, the objects measure at least 1,500 feet tall...
报告称有两个物体进入俄罗斯领空
Two are reported to have penetrated Russian airspace.
一个在西伯利亚 另一个在黑海沿岸的
One in Siberia, and the other off the coast of the Black...
海洋上面
...above the ocean.
目前 共有十二个不明物体
So far, there are 12 unidentified objects
分布全球
spread across the globe.
从其位置上来看并无逻辑
There is no obvious logic to their locations
没有证据表明这些飞船正在运行
and no evidence that the ships are even occu...
有这种考虑 即这可能是一种
...entertain the idea that if it is a kind of vessel,
无人驾驶的飞船
it may be unmanned.
无论如何 我们有应对此类事态的预案
Regardless, we have a protocol for scenarios like this.
在星期二的特别事件之后
After Tuesday's extraordinary events,
总统今晨宣布进入紧急状态
the President this morning has declared a state of emergency,
仅在蒙大拿州就部署了
with as many as 5,000 National Guard
有五千名国民警卫队
being deployed to the state of Montana alone.
边境被封锁 航班被停飞
Borders are closed and flights have been grounded,
有上百万的游客被滞留
stranding millions of travelers.
人们疯狂抢购汽油 水和食物
Panic buying of gas, water and food
事态持续扩大
continues to escalate,
联邦政府暂时解除了
and federal authorities have temporarily lifted
对执法部门的所有加班禁令
all caps on overtime for law enforcement.
烟酒枪械管理局已经暂时停止发放新的持枪许可
The ATF has put a temporary ban on new gun licenses,
迫使许多的狩猎设备和武器
forcing many independent suppliers of
的独立供应商不得不
hunting equipment and firearms
暂停对公众开放
to close their doors to the public.
已经四十八小时过去了 在十二个不明飞行的降落地
Forty-eight hours later and no further development...
两天了
Two days...
还没有任何进展
...from the site of the 12 UFOs.
公众已经在期待我们
...and already, the public expects us
来了解答案
to know the answers.
我是韦伯上校
I'm Colonel G.T. Weber.
我们从未正式见过面
We never formally met,
不过两年前 你为军方情报部做过
but two years ago, you did some Farsi translations
波斯语的翻译
for Army Intelligence.
哦
Oh.
你对那些叛乱者的视频翻译的效率挺高的
You made quick work of those insurgent videos.
你对叛乱者的处理效率也挺高的
You made quick work of those insurgents.
凡是涉及到翻译
You are on the top of everyone's list
你是公认最顶尖的
when it comes to translations.
你的单一范围背景调查还有两年的权限
And you have another two years in your SSBI,
所以你仍有接触最高机密的许可
so you still have top-secret clearance.
这就是为什么我会出现在你的办公室里 而不是在伯克利
That's why I'm in your office and not at Berkeley.
好吧
Okay.
我想请你翻译些东西
I have something I need you to translate for me.
你们为什么来这里
Why are you here?
你们 你们能理解我们的语言吗
Can you... Can you understand us?
你们从哪里来
Where did you come from?
现在你听过了 你有什么想法吗
Now you heard it. What do you make of it?
那就是
Is that...
是的
Yes.
有多少
How many?
-什么有多少 -有多少在说话
- How many what? - Um, how many, um, speaking?
两个
Two.
假设它们不是同时在说话
Assume they were not speaking at the same time.
你确定吗 它们有嘴吗
Are you sure? Did they have mouths...
你要是翻译这个的话 你怎么做
How would you approach translating this?
你有没有听到什么词汇 短语
Do you hear any words? Phrases?
我不 我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
那你能告诉我什么吗
So what can you tell me?
我能说的就是不可能仅根据音频文件
I can tell you that it's impossible
来翻译这些
to translate from an audio file.
我得亲自到现场 跟它们进行互动
I would need to be there, to interact with them.
做波斯语翻译的时候你也没互动啊
You didn't need that with the Farsi translations.
我不需要是因为我会波斯语
I didn't need it because I already knew the language,
但是这个 这是 呃
but this... This is... Ah...
我知道你想干什么
I know what you're doing.
-那你说说我在要干嘛 -我是不会带你去蒙大拿的
- Tell me what I'm doing. - I'm not taking you to Montana.
我不能让别人把最高机密许可
It's all I can do to keep it from turning into a tourist site
当成旅游景点的门票
for everybody who has a TS clearance.
我只是告诉你完成这项工作
I'm just telling you what it would take
需要什么
to do this job.
我不是来商量的
This is not a negotiation.
如果我离开这里 你就没机会了
If I leave here, your chance is gone.
再见
Good day.
上校
Colonel?
你刚才说伯克利
You mentioned Berkeley.
接下来你是不是要去询问丹佛斯
Are you going to ask Danvers next?
可能吧
Maybe.
在你让他工作之前
Before you commit to him,
问问他梵文里战争一词及其翻译
ask him the Sanskrit word for war and its translation.
在今晚的中国和俄罗斯在联合国加入磋商后
An agreement on sharing scientific discoveries
有望达成
looks closer tonight,
一个科学发现共享协议
as Russia and China join talks at the United Nations.
与此同时 世界范围内的金融市场处于危机中
Meanwhile, financial markets across the world are in crisis
道琼斯工业指数下跌
as the Dow Jones Industrial Average fell
超过两千点
over 2,000 points...
早上好
Morning.
上校
Colonel?
伽维斯提
Gavisti.
他说这表示“争论”
He says it means "An argument."
你觉得那个词是什么意思
What do you say it means?
渴望更多的牛
A desire for more cows.
装好你的行李
Pack your bags.
-好吧 给我二十分钟 -十分钟后起飞
- All right. Give me 20 minutes? - Takeoff in ten.
班克斯博士 这边请
Dr. Banks. Right this way, please.
收到 准备前往
Contact and ready to approach...
抱歉 班克斯博士 我来检查一下你的安全带
Excuse me, Dr. Banks, let me make sure you're properly secured.
你还好吗
You okay?
对不起 我刚才没听见你在说什么
Sorry, I couldn't hear what you were saying.
“语言”是文明的基石
"Language is the foundation of civilization.
它是将人们联结在一起的胶水
"It is the glue that holds a people together.
它是在冲突中最先使用的武器
"It is the first weapon drawn in a conflict."
露易丝 这是伊恩・唐纳利 露易丝・班克斯 伊恩・唐纳利
Louise, this is Ian Donnelly. Louise Banks, Ian Donnelly.
这就是打过招呼了
That's quite a greeting.
是啊 你写的这个
Yeah, well, you wrote it.
嗯
Yeah.
这就是你写来做序言的东西
It's the kind of thing you write as a preface.
博得读者眼球
Dazzle them with the basics.
是 挺好的 即便是错的
Yeah, it's great. Even if it's wrong.
错了
It's wrong?
嗯 文明的基石不是语言
Well, the cornerstone of civilization isn't language,
而是科学
it's science.
伊恩是来自阿拉莫斯国家实验室的理论物理学家
Ian is a theoretical physicist from Los Alamos.
你向我汇报 但当你在壳里时
You'll be reporting to me, but you'll be working with him
你和他一起共事
when you're in the shell.
它们管那个不明飞行物叫壳
That's what they're calling the UFO.
首要目的 它们从何来 何所求
Priority one: what do they want and where are they from?
除此以外 它们是怎么来到这里的
And beyond that, how did they get here?
它们能进行超光速旅行吗
Are they capable of faster-than-light travel?
我准备了一系列的问题要问
I've prepared a list of questions to go over,
以二进制序列的“握手”为开始
starting with a series of "Handshake" Binary sequences...
我们能不能在向它们问数学题之前
How about we just talk to them
先跟它们交流起来
before we start throwing math problems at them?
这就是为什么同时请了你们俩
This is why you're both here.
我来端咖啡
I'll bring the coffee.
与外星人一起喝咖啡
Coffee with some aliens.
你带他们两个去凯特勒博士那里去
I want you to take these two to Dr. Kettler.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
请跟着这位上尉去医务室
Follow the captain to medical.
这只需要几分钟就好
It should take just a few minutes,
然后我们就开始
and then we'll get started.
把背包交给我们 请把手机交给我
We'll take care of your bag. I'll take your cell phones.
手机拿出来
Cell phones!
跟着我
Follow me.
把这些穿上 你们得一直穿着它们
Put these on. You're gonna wear them at all times.
长官 他们到了
Sir, they're here.
露易丝・班克斯 伊恩・唐纳利
Louise Banks? Ian Donnelly?
你们上一顿饭什么时候吃的
When was the last time either of you have eaten?
-昨晚 -我也是
- Last night. - Same.
上一次在压力状态下做事
Last time you did something stressful?
现在算吗
Does now count?
开个玩笑
Just saying...
哦 被抬进救伤直升机的是谁
Uh, who was being carted off in the medevac?
不是所有人都可以经受住这样的经历的
Not everyone is able to process experiences like this.
我需要抽一些你的血
I'm gonna get some blood from you
然后给你打一针疫苗
and give you an immunization dose
能抵御多种细菌威胁
that covers a battery of bacterial threats.
请你在这里签个字 把袖子撸上去
Could you sign these, please? And roll up your sleeves.
你们谁有幽闭恐惧症
Either of you claustrophobic?
-没有 -没有
- No. - No.
目前有没有在用药 对什么过敏
Currently taking any medications? Allergies?
有怀孕吗
Pregnant?
没有
No.
加强剂会对你的身体系统产生冲击
The booster is a kick to your system,
所以你会感觉到一些副作用
so you may experience some side effects,
比如恶心 头晕 头疼
nausea, dizziness, headaches,
耳鸣之类的
a ringing in your ears, like you have tinnitus.
他们不管怎样都不离开
They wouldn't go, either way.
你看到他怎么了吗
You see what's happening to him?
这到底是怎么运行的
How does this even work?
读数没变化
The readings do not change,
但 我不懂
but I don't know,
就好像我们是一片纸上的虫子
it's like we're insects on a piece of paper,
他们在让我们自己撤退
and they're easing us out of the house.
在一百一十二分钟十九秒后
At exactly 112 minutes and 19 seconds,
重力开始起变化 让我们滑出房间
gravity starts to shift and slides us out of the room.
对此你有科学解释吗
Have you found a scientific explanation for it?
比如 这对它们来说有利
Like, is it for them?
哦 不 我觉得是为我们方便的
Uh, no. We think it's for us.
在房间内部的空气似乎并不流通
Air doesn't seem to circulate inside the chamber,
所以两小时后 我们的氧气就消耗光了
so after about two hours, we run out of oxygen.
往那个房间泵送空气用不了十八个小时
It doesn't take 18 hours to pump fresh air into a room.
大气
Atmosphere...
你说什么
Excuse me?
如果它们的大气和地球上的不一样
If their atmosphere is different from Earth,
在它们每次打开舱门之前
it would certainly take hours
它们得将氧气含量及气压进行重新调整
to rebalance their O2 content and pressure for us
已达到我们的适应范围内
every time they open their door.
那么你是说它们能令我们窒息 如果它们想的话
So, they could suffocate us if they wanted.
这位是来自中情局的哈尔彭特工
This is Agent Halpern with the CIA.
我带你们去你们的工位
Let me get you two to your stations.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
记住 我们得尽快得到答案
Remember, we need answers as soon as possible.
它们何所求 来自何方
What do they want? Where are they from?
以及为什么来这里
Why are they here?
这是首要任务
This is the priority.
大家 这位是伊恩・唐纳利博士
Everyone, this is Dr. Ian Donnelly.
他负责带领这个队
He'll be running this team here.
它们有没有对什么作出反应
Have they responded to anything?
形状 模式 数字 斐波那契数列
Shapes, patterns, numbers, Fibonacci?
当它们回复“你好”的时候
We can't tell what they're saying
我们并不知道它们在说什么
when they respond to "Hello," So...
别太急于求成
Don't get ahead of yourself.
你们得出什么了
What have you figured out?
我们这才刚刚开始 各位早上好
We're just getting started. Good morning!
这是露易丝・班克斯博士 她负责带你们队
This is Dr. Louise Banks. She'll be heading your team.
很高兴见到你
It's a pleasure meeting you.
班克斯博士接手沃克博士的任务
Dr. Banks is taking over the mission from Dr. Walker.
那是一个十五分钟警报
That's a 15-minute warning.
你以前潜过水吗
You scuba-dive before?
我们要去的地方有哪种辐射
What kind of radiation exposure are we walking into?
就是形式上的以防万一 为安全考虑
Nominal. These are just for safety.
那么 有没有和那些的肢体接触
So, is there any physical contact with the, um...
有人和我一样讲不出“外星人”吗
Am I the only one having trouble saying "Aliens"?
那里有一面墙 像是玻璃墙
There's a wall. Like, a glass wall.
你碰不到它们
You can't get to them.
它们长什么样子
So, what do they look like?
你马上就能看到了 加快
You'll see soon enough. Hurry up.
防护服一开始很笨重
The suits are clumsy at first,
但你会习惯的
but you get used to them.
我开第二辆车
I'll open a second vehicle.
我们几分钟就到
We'll be there in a few minutes.
确保你把住什么东西
Make sure you hold on to something.
收到 秃鹰 我们会监视 但不启动 完毕
Copy, Condor. We will observe, but not initiate. Over.
小心
Watch your step.
我们会保持阿尔法频道畅通 完毕
We'll keep Alpha channel open. Over.
阿尔法 请注意 湿度从昨天开始增加了
Alpha, be advised. Humidity increased since yesterday.
每隔十八小时
Every 18 hours,
底部的门就会打开
the door opens up at the bottom.
这就是我们要去的地方
That's where we go in.
零移动 阿尔法可以前进 完毕
Zero movement. Alpha detail, clear to proceed. Over.
收到 秃鹰
Copy, Condor.
现在开始上升 完毕
Beginning our ascent now. Over.
十英尺
Ten feet.
五英尺
Five feet.
二 一
Two, one...
阿尔法可以进入前厅
Alpha clear to enter antechamber.
开始行动
Moving into position.
距目标三十英尺
Thirty feet from target.
防护服遥测系统正常
Suit telemetry now full strength,
但是有未知干扰
despite unknown interference.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
氧气含量 百分之二十点三
Oxygen level: 20.3%.
未检测到可知毒物 完毕
No known contaminates. Over.
无线信号正在减弱
Radio signals are decreasing.
百分之九十 百分之八十五
90%, 85%...
好吧 就这样发生了
Yeah, that just happened.
好了 我们上去吧
All right, let's move!
时不要浪费时间
Time is wasting.
你准备好了吗 准备好了吗
You ready? You ready?
来吧
Let's do it!
秃鹰 我和马克斯上尉先上 完毕
Condor, I'm proceeding first with Captain Marks, over.
前厅重力微乎其微 完毕
Gravity nominal in the antechamber. Over!
一切都好 长官
It's all good, sir.
你可以上来
You can proceed.
待命 好的 上来
Stand by! Okay, bring it up.
心肺功能减弱
Vitals are low.
无线信号稳定在百分之七十五 完毕
Radio signal strength stable at 75%. Over.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好
Yeah.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks?
你可以的 来吧
You can do this. Come on.
我不知道 我 我认为
I don't know. I... I think...
抓住她
Grab her.
唐纳利 你怎么样
Donnelly, are you all right?
唐纳利博士 你还好吗
Dr. Donnelly, you good?
Dr. Donnelly, are you all right?
请回答 完毕
Please respond. Over.
我还好
Yeah.
老天呐
Holy fuck!
我们要去那
We're gonna go down there,
你们开始工作
and you're gonna start your job.
-好的 -行吗
- Okay. - Okay?
可以
Okay.
大家听好 前进
Everybody, move out!
阿尔法准备好了
Alpha detail is in position.
团队准备好了
Team is in position.
我们正在前进
We're on the move.
秃鹰 阿尔法到达正厅了
Condor, Alpha's now in the nave.
正在安装设备和遥感系统 完毕
Setting up equipment and telemetry. Over.
所以 接下来怎么办
So, what happens now?
他们会来的
They arrive.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks?
你可以开始了
You can start.
在气密室中
...in airlock.
在通过气密室门之前不要停下
Do not stop until you have passed the airlock door.
不要脱掉防护服
Do not attempt to remove hazmat suits
在没有工作人员帮助下
without assistance from authorized personnel.
防护服
hazmat suits
在没有工作人员的帮助下
without assistance from authorized personnel.
等一下 一分钟 就一分钟
Wait. Just a minute. Just a minute.
安全
Clear.
-好的 -请把脚移出来
- All right. - Step on out, please.
拿着它
Now hold that.
我被炒了吗
Am I fired?
你比上一个好多了
You're better than the last guy.
这没有让我好受些
That doesn't make me feel any better.
到凌晨两点你们还有些思考的时间
You both have till 02:00 hours to figure something out.
好的 然后呢
Okay. What happens then?
你们再去
You go back in.
十二处着陆的发现
Violence continues to spread
使得暴力在美国持续蔓延
across the US today in the wake of the 12 landings.
在国家警卫队
The president has declared
对连续三天晚上的打砸抢
a mandatory dusk-to-dawn curfew
镇压失败后
after the crackdown by the National Guard failed
总统下达了对黄昏到黎明的宵禁命令
to prevent a third night of looting across the country.
在南达科他州 一百四十四个
In North Dakota, 144 members of
圣劳伦斯五旬节派成员
the Saint Lawrence Pentecostal Cult
在点燃易燃物后死亡
are feared dead after they set their compound ablaze.
他们网站上宣称外星人的到来
Their website claims the arrival of the aliens
说明了一个预言
set in motion a prophesy that...
我们将在十五分钟后行动 你有什么新信息吗
Uh, we're up in 15. You got any new intel?
是的 我们有一些他们的声音
Yeah, we've been playing back some of their sounds.
你们怎么得到的
Where does that get you?
他们向我们发出了声音
Well, they play audio back at us,
从一个看不见的地方
from an unseen source.
什么的声音
Audio of what?
他们在房间里的一些交流
Uh, it's bits of conversation from the room.
随意的对话片段
Random clips of dialogue.
说真的 我们什么都没得到
Really, we have nothing.
距出发十四分钟
T-minus 14 minutes to shell access.
距出发九分钟
T-minus 9 minutes to shell access.
那是干什么的
What's that for?
视觉辅助手段
A visual aid.
听着 我永远都不可能说他们的语言
Look, I'm never gonna be able to speak their words,
假设他们说的是种语言的话
if they are talking,
但他们可能会有一些书面语言
but they might have some sort of written language
或用于视觉交流的东西
or basis for visual communication.
好的 我们开始吧
Okay. Let's get started.
人类
Human.
"Human."
我是人类 你们呢
I'm human. What are you?
人类
Human.
我的天哪
Oh my God!
你记录下来了吗
Are you getting this?
是的 长官 我正把这个传回营地
Yes, sir! It's uploading back to base camp.
露易丝 这太不可思议了
Louise, that's incredible.
人类
Human.
好的 慢一点
Okay, slow down now.
慢一点
Slow down.
我不想打击你的成功
I don't wanna take away from your success in there,
但是 班克斯博士 这真的是正确的方法吗
but Dr. Banks, is this really the right approach?
尝试教给他们说和读
Trying to teach them how to speak and read?
这要花费更长时间
That's gotta take longer.
你错了 这更快
You're wrong. It's faster.
你在那做的每件事
Everything you do in there,
我都要给一屋子的人解释
I have to explain to a room full of men
他们的问题都是
whose first and last question is...
这将怎样被用来对付我们
"How can this be used against us?"
所以你要给我更多的解释
So you're gonna have to give me more than that.
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
那是什么
What is that?
在一七七零年
In 1770,
詹姆斯・库克船长的船
Captain James Cook's ship ran aground
在澳大利亚海边搁浅
off the coast of Australia,
他带了一队人深入
and he led a party into the country,
遇到了土著人
and they met the Aboriginal people.
一个水手指着
One of the sailors pointed at
跳来跳去
the animals that hop around
将它们的孩子放在育儿袋中的动物
and put their babies in their pouch,
问它们是什么
and he asked what they were,
土著人回答 Kangaroo[袋鼠]
and the Aborigine said, "Kangaroo."
你想说什么
And the point is?
没过多久他们知道了
It wasn't till later that they learned that
Kangaroo的意思是我听不懂 所以
"Kangaroo" Means "I don't understand." So,
我这么做是为了我们不把那里的事情翻译错
I need this so that we don't misinterpret things in there.
否则 将会花费十倍以上的时间
Otherwise, this is gonna take 10 times as long.
现在我接受你的解释
I can sell that for now.
但是在下次进去之前
But I need you to submit your vocabulary words
我需要你上交你的词汇
before the next session.
好的
Fair.
记住土著人所遭受的苦难
And remember what happened to the Aborigines.
一个更加高级的种族几乎将他们赶尽杀绝
A more advanced race nearly wiped them out.
那是个好故事
It's a good story.
谢谢
Thanks.
假的
It's not true.
但它证明了我的观点
But it proves my point.
我认为我们可以复制一些基本数字序列
We think we were able to reproduce
发回给他们
some prime number sequences back at them.
还是小有成就的
So that's something.
那么 祝贺你 你像只鹦鹉
Well, congratulations. You're a parrot.
比那难多了 你个混蛋
It's a lot more than that, you cheeky bastard,
你没看到吗
don't you see?
他们似乎不懂我们的代数
They can't seem to follow our algebra,
但是复杂的行为 他们懂
but complex behaviors, that clicks.
这根本说不通 不是吗
Well that doesn't make any sense at all, does it?
问题是 不是每个人都理解我们
Problem is, not everyone shares our policy
向外星人的开放态度
of being open with the aliens.
你见过尚将军吗
Have you met General Shang?
他的命令就像多米诺骨牌
The call sign for him is Big Domino.
不管尚将军干什么
Whatever Shang does,
至少有四个国家会跟随他
at least four other nations will follow.
露易丝 我们今天要上去
Louise? We have to gain ground today.
好的
Okay.
-你的词汇表呢 -在这
- You have a vocabulary list for me? - I do.
你准备教他们你和伊恩的名字
You're gonna teach them your name and Ian's?
是的 这样我们就能知道他们的名字了
Yes, so that we can learn
如果他们有名字的话
their names if they have names,
然后教给他们代词
and then introduce pronouns later.
这些都是小学单词
These are all grade-school words:
吃 走
eat, walk.
解释一下
Help me understand.
好的
Okay. Um...
噢 不不不 别擦上边
Oh, no, no, no! Not the top!
好的 这是你想知道的 对吗
Okay, this is where you wanna get to, right?
-是的 -好的
- That is the question. - Okay.
所以 首先我们需要确保
So, first, we need to make sure that
他们知道什么是问题
they understand what a question is.
那么 问题的本质就是
Okay, the nature of a request for information
带有答案的信息
along with a response.
接着 我们需要让他们分清
Then, we need to clarify the difference between
个体的你和集体的你
a specific "You" And a collective "You,"
因为我们不想知道为什么其中的一个人来了
because we don't wanna know why Joe Alien is here,
我们想知道的是为什么他们全都来了
we want to know why they all landed.
理解“目的”需要引入“意图”这个概念
And purpose requires an understanding of intent.
我们需要搞清楚
We need to find out:
他们能做有意识的决定吗
do they make conscious choices?
或者说他们的动机是本能的
Or is their motivation so instinctive
他们并不能理解什么是问题
that they don't understand a "Why" Question at all?
最重要的是
And... And biggest of all,
我们需要和他们有足够多的词汇
we need to have enough vocabulary with them
以便理解他们的答案
that we understand their answer.
我明白了
I get it.
按照你的词汇表来
Stick to your list.
只是
Just
不要增加任何东西
don't add anything to it.
...是二点九七
...are at 2.97.
氧气含量 百分之二十一点四 完毕
Oxygen level: 21.4%. Over.
秃鹰 阿尔法现在在中厅
Condor, Alpha's now in the nave.
设置好装备和遥感系统 完毕
Setting up equipment and telemetry. Over.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
露易丝 露易丝 我是露易丝
Louise. Louise. I am Louise.
那是什么
What is that?
那是一个新符号吗 我看不懂
Is that a new symbol? I can't tell.
我不知道 我认为那还是人类的意思
I don't know. I think it's the symbol for human again.
他只是在尾部加了一点弯曲
It just has a little curl on the end,
可能是问句的意思
maybe to indicate a question.
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道 露易丝
I don't know, Louise.
我认为他们很疑惑
I think they're getting confused.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks,
你可以进行下一个单词了
perhaps we should move on to the next word.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks!
我没事
It's okay.
发生了什么
What's going on?
嘿 你在干嘛呢
Hey! What are you doing?
没事 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
他们需要看清我
They need to see me.
她把防护服脱了
She's taking off her hazmat suit.
这可以吗
Is it okay?
你有被感染的危险
You're risking contamination.
他们需要看请我
They need to see me.
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks...
Dr. Banks.
她向屏幕走去了
She's walking towards the screen.
我们要中止任务吗
Should we abort?
请求收到 等待后续命令
Recourse noted. Stand by for further orders.
回到自己的位置上去
Go back to your stations.
这才是合适的自我介绍 嘿
Now that's a proper introduction. Hey.
露易丝
Louise.
我是露易丝
I am Louise.
伊恩 你想介绍下你自己吗
Ian, do you want to introduce yourself?
好
Uh, yeah.
露易丝
Louise.
管它呢
Screw it!
每个人都会死 对吗
Everybody dies, right?
长官 唐纳利脱掉了防护服
Sir, Donnelly is taking off his hazmat suit.
请求中止
Permission to abort?
继续
Continue the session.
伊恩
Ian.
露易丝
Louise.
你们
You...
你们呢
Who are you?
我认为这是他们的名字
I think those are their names.
它们有名字
They have names.
所以 我们要叫他们什么呢
So, what are we gonna call them?
我不知道
I don't know.
艾伯特和科斯特洛怎么样
I was thinking Abbott and Costello.
可以
Yeah.
-可以吗 -是的 我喜欢
- Yeah? - Yeah, I like it.
我喜欢
I like it.
哇哦
Wow!
一队 下车
Team 1, exit your vehicle
直接去消毒营
and proceed directly ahead to the decontamination tent.
开着呼吸器直到进入仪器室
Leave your respirator on until you reach the equipment room.
我知道 嘘
I know. Shhh!
二队 下车
Team 2, exit your vehicles
去消毒营
and continue to the decontamination tent.
开着呼吸机
Leave your respirators on
在到达仪器室之前
and do not hesitate
不要停下
until you have reached the equipment room.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
精疲力竭
Overworked.
我猜不需要我告诉你
Well, I guess I don't need to tell you
你把自己置于危险之中
you're putting yourself at risk.
还没有发现有毒放射物
There's no signs of radiation poisoning yet.
看看你的血液检测情况
We'll see how your blood tests look.
现在 我要给你另一种药
For now, I'm gonna give you another boost.
好的
Okay.
没有放射物
No radiation.
也没有检测到其他物质
Nothing else we can detect either,
但我还是要给他们打一针混合疫苗
but I'd give them a strong cocktail, regardless.
这是我们第一次取得这么大的进步
It's the first time we've made significant progress.
好吧 这风险我们担了
All right. We'll take the risk.
好了 亲爱的
Okay, honey...
那里发生了什么
What is going on there?
亲爱的
Honey...
告诉我
Just tell me!
你不需要担心 好吗
You don't need to worry, okay?
-我怎么能不担心 -冷静点
- How can I not worry? - Just calm down.
冷静下来
Just calm down.
贝基问我怪兽会不会把爸爸杀了
Becky asked me if the monsters are going to kill Daddy!
亲爱的 这不会发生的
Honey, it's not gonna happen.
你要好好的
Just stay safe.
你不需要担心
You don't need to worry.
求你了 我好害怕
Please! I'm so scared!
所有低级别外国语言学研究者
All junior xenolinguistics
和科学人员一定要遵守
and science personnel must observe
全体宵禁 除非得到指挥官特别授权
general curfew unless expressly authorized
可以延长工作时间
for extended work hours by unit COs.
有效宵禁时间截止到两千二百小时
Curfew in effect as of 2200 hours.
所有的加班工作人员 火灾警戒员 和值夜班的人
Notice to all late workers, fire watchers and night staff.
整晚都有物品供应
Effective immediately, midnight rations will be served all night.
我们对于七脚怪
Here are some of the many things
还是一无所知
we don't know about heptapods.
希腊语中 Hepta指的是七 Pod指的是脚
Greek. Hepta, "Seven. " Pod, "Foot."
七只脚 七脚怪
Seven feet. Heptapod.
他们到底是什么
Who are they?
试图更加深入的了解他们
Trying to answer this in any meaningful way
而现实总是让人失望
is hampered by the fact that,
在外面 能看见他们的样子 听见他们的声音
outside being able to see them and hear them,
但七脚怪完全没有留下任何踪迹
the heptapods leave absolutely no footprint.
对其飞船的化学分析也没有任何结果
The chemical composition of their spaceship is unknown.
壳体不会产出废料 不会排出气体 也没有辐射
The shell emits no waste, no gas, no radiation.
假设这些壳体之间能够交流
Assuming that the shells communicate with each other,
却不被人类所发现
they do so without detection.
壳体之间的空气不会
The air between the shells is untroubled
受到声波和光波的影响
by sonic emission or light wave.
那他们是科学家吗 还是游客
Are they scientists? Or tourists?
假设他们科学家
If they're scientists,
但并没有询问一大堆的问题
they don't seem to ask a lot of questions.
为什么他们停在了这儿
Why did they park where they did?
世界上最有学识的专家也无法解释
The world's most decorated experts can't crack that one.
最有可能的原因是
The most plausible theory is
他们选择停在地球上
that they chose places on Earth
几乎不会有闪电的地方
with the lowest incidence of lightning strikes.
但是也有例外
But there are exceptions.
另一个可能理论是
The next most plausible theory is that
在1980年 希娜・伊斯顿的歌曲
Sheena Easton had a hit song
在这些地方红极一时
at each of these sites in 1980.
因此我们还是一无所知
So, we just don't know.
他们是怎样交流的
How do they communicate?
露易丝在这儿使我们自惭形秽
Here, Louise is putting us all to shame.
取得的第一个突破是
The first breakthrough was
发现了七脚怪所说的话
to discover that there's no correlation
和所写的字之间没有任何关联
between what a heptapod says and what a heptapod writes.
和所有人类文字不同的是
Unlike all written human languages,
他们使用的是意符文字
their writing is semasiographic.
文字代表了意思 但不代表发音
It conveys meaning. It doesn't represent sound.
可能他们觉得我们的文字
Perhaps they view our form of writing
完全是多此一举
as a wasted opportunity,
浪费了一次交流的机会
passing up a second communications channel.
我们得感谢在巴基斯坦的朋友
We have our friends in Pakistan to thank
对七脚怪文字的研究
for their study of how heptapods write,
因为不像说话 意音文字不会随着时间改变其意思
because unlike speech, a logogram is free of time.
就像他们的飞船和身体一样
Like their ship or their bodies,
他们的文字不存在
their written language has no forward
具体的顺序
or backward direction.
语言学家称其为非线性拼写法
Linguists call this non-linear orthography,
这不由的让人怀疑 他们也是这么思考的吗
which raises the question, "Is this how they think?"
想象一下你要用双手写一个句子
Imagine you wanted to write a sentence using two hands,
分别从两边开始书写
starting from either side.
你必须清楚你想要用的每个词语
You would have to know each word you wanted to use,
和它们所占据的空间的大小
as well as how much space they would occupy.
七脚怪能毫不费力
A heptapod can write a complex sentence
在两秒中内写一个复杂的句子
in two seconds, effortlessly.
而人类要用一个月才做出简单的回复
It's taken us a month to make the simplest reply.
关于七脚怪如何扩充词汇
Next, expanding vocabulary.
路易斯认为至少需要一个月
Louise thinks it could easily take another month
才能弄明白
to be ready for that.
嘿
Hey...
你好
Oh, hey.
韦伯在找你
Weber's looking for you.
我知道 不然我为什么躲在这里
Yeah, well, why do you think I'm hiding out here?
上来吧
Come on up!
谢谢
Thanks.
这儿真美 对吧
Nice out here, huh?
确实 风景很美
Yeah, it's a nice view.
远离那些噪音
Away from the noise.
你知道吗 我刚正好想到你
You know, I was just thinking about you.
你像数学家那样解决语言问题
You approach language like a mathematician.
我没猜错吧
You know that, right?
我就当你在夸我
I will take that as a compliment.
就是在夸你啊
Yeah, well, it is.
当你指导我们绕过那些
As I watch you steer us around these communication traps
我根本没有察觉的语言陷阱
that I didn't even know existed,
心里在说 什么
it's like, "What?"
我猜这就是我单身的原因
I guess that's why I'm single.
相信我 就算你懂得如何沟通
Trust me, you can understand communication
到最后依然还是单身
and still end up single.
我感觉里面发生的所有事
I feel like everything that happens in there
都要靠我们俩解决了
comes down to the two of us.
那难道不是件好事吗
Yeah, that's a good thing though, right?
你和我
You and I?
看到每天和我们一起工作的废柴
Have you seen the jokers that we're working with?
我就在想 幸好还有你
Thank God I've got you!
今晚
Tonight,
第一张外星人的照片在疯狂传播
the first photograph of the aliens goes viral.
生物污染是蒙大拿存在的
Biological contamination is a major risk factor
最主要的威胁
at the Montana site.
环保组织如是说
So say environmental pressure groups.
在华盛顿 有80万人游行
800,000 march on Washington
抗议政府对危机的处理
to protest the government's handling of the crisis.
接下来会有更多的新闻报道
All this, and more special coverage.
首先和里面的不明物体进行沟通
First contact with whoever it is that is inside that thing,
猜猜谁在操作这场秀
and who's running the show?
当然是政府
The government.
听好了 就是那个
That's right, folks, the same government
破坏了我们的医疗保险 搞砸了我们的军队的政府
who ruined our healthcare and bankrupted our military.
看看这些人啊
Look at these people!
大多数都是手无寸铁的老百姓
Most of them don't even have guns!
我们可能会遭遇全面的入侵
We could be facing a full-scale invasion.
我们的总统只是干等着
Our president's willing to sit back
让他们大摇大摆地夺走我们的家园
and let them waltz in and take our country.
我们要玩完了啊
We are falling asleep at the wheel, people!
你们知道我没有胡说八道
You know what I'm talking about. I know you do.
我们现在最应该做的就是
What if the smartest thing we could do right now
展现我们的武力
would be to give them a show of force?
让他们知道我们的厉害
I'm talking about a shot across the bow.
你认为怎么样
What do you think?
第一位来电者 你好
Caller No.1, you're on the air.
发表下你的看法
What do you think?
这个词是什么意思
What's this word?
行星
Planet.
就像地球是一个行星
That's, like, um... The Earth is a planet.
想看看我为伽利略老师课上做的东西吗
Want to see my project for Miss Garriott's class?
当然 小可爱
Yeah, little nose.
我们要自己制作电视节目
We had to make up our own TV show.
如果我们有的话
If we had one.
这两个人是谁
And who are those two people?
你和爸爸
That's you and Dad.
电视名字叫做
The show is called
和小动物们说话的妈妈和爸爸
"Mommy and Daddy talk to Animals."
哦
Oh!
太可爱了
Well, it's lovely.
好吧
Okay...
呃
Um...
你可以因为爸爸和妈妈的事情而感到不开心
You know it's okay to be sad that your dad and I...
我知道 我没有
I know. I'm not.
因为我们都很爱你
'Cause we both love you very much.
我知道 只是张卡通画 并不是真的
I know. It's just a cartoon. It's not real.
露易丝
Louise?
你还好吗
You all right?
我挺好的
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
我也不好怎么说
I'm not sure it's something I can... I can explain.
你上次去凯特勒医生那儿检查是什么时候
When was your last checkup with Dr. Kettler?
我没事
I'm okay.
我要去透透气了
I'm gonna get some air.
-我没事了 -好吧
- I'm okay. - All right.
我挺好的
I'm fine. Yep.
你怎么样
How you feeling?
呃
Um...
我想睡一觉 但我挺好的
I need some sleep, but I'm fine.
好吧
Yeah.
我看过有关这些的
You know, I was doing some reading, um,
书籍
about this idea
里面说到 如果你沉浸于一门外语中
that if you immerse yourself into a foreign language,
就能重新构建你的大脑
then you can actually rewire your brain.
是萨皮尔沃夫理论
The Sapir-Whorf hypothesis.
对的
Mm-hmm.
这个理论
The theory that, uh...
这个理论说到
It... It's the theory that, uh,
你所说的语言决定了
the language you speak determines
你思维的方式
how you think and...
还会影响你看待事情的态度
Yeah. It affects how you see everything.
这真是
It was, uh...
我很好奇
I'm curious...
你会梦到他们的语言吗
Are you dreaming in their language?
梦到过几次 但是
I may have had a few dreams, but I don't...
我不认为那意味着我不能胜任这份工作
I don't think that that makes me unfit to do this job.
你睡过了吗
Did you sleep?
睡了一会
A little.
你会普通话吗
Do you know Mandarin?
它在移动
It is shifting.
你将听到的声音来自
The voice you're about to hear
中国军队的长官
belongs to a Chinese military chief...
尚将军
General Shang.
带上吧
Pull it up!
这儿有他和别人说话的卫星录像
We got a satellite feed here of who he's talking to,
如果你想看看的话
if you want to look.
等下 倒一点
Wait, go back.
停
Stop.
他说这十二个不明物体
He's saying that each of the 12
会提供高科技
is offering advanced technology.
再倒回去 放吧
Go back again. And play.
呃
Um...
我们的科学队伍正试图破解密码
"Our science team is attempting to decode the sets."
密码 我不知道那是什么意思
"Sets." I don't know what that means.
一些有利的东西
Something about advantage,
色子 番子 花牌
suits, honor and, uh, flowers.
我不
I don't...
我不知道
I don't know. That's all.
我不知道那什么意思
I don't know what it means either.
一个小时前 中国调动了军队
An hour ago, China mobilized forces.
现在 俄罗斯也紧随其后
And now, Russia's following suit.
尚要开始搞事情了
Shang's about to start something.
跟着服装 服装
Following suit. Suits.
色子 番子 花牌
Suits, honor, flowers...
上校 那些全是麻将里面的牌
Colonel, those are all tile sets in mah-jongg.
我的天
God, are they...
他们用麻将和七脚怪交流吗
Are they using a game to converse with their heptapods?
可能 为什么
Maybe. Why?
打个比方 如果我们教他们下棋 而非英语
Well, let's say that I taught them chess instead of English.
每场对话都可以是一场游戏
Every conversation would be a game.
每个想法都可以通过对完之后的输和赢来表达
Every idea expressed through opposition, victory, defeat.
你明白了吗
You see the problem?
我知道了
Hmm...
如果我只给你一个锤子
If all I ever gave you was a hammer...
那么所有事都是钉子
Everything's a nail.
我们得问出那个问题了
We need to ask the big question.
准备好了吗
Ready or not.
我懂了 但在那之间
Yeah, I know, but between there and there.
是时候出发了
Well, it's time to go.
好的
Okay...
七脚怪的目的
Heptapods' purpose.
七脚怪的目的 地球 你们的目的是什么
Heptapod purpose Earth. What is your purpose?
只有科斯特洛了吗
Do we only have Costello?
很好 你来了
Okay. There you are.
它说了什么
What does it say?
提供武器
Offer weapon.
你看见他们写的了
You saw what they wrote!
他们还没搞懂那个词的意思
Using a word they don't fully understand.
-可能只是个要求 -是警告
- Could be a request. - A warning.
够了 露易丝你说
Enough! Louise?
我们不知道他们是否理解了
We don't know if they understand
武器和工具之间的区别
the difference between a weapon and a tool.
我们的语言和文化一样复杂
Our language, like our culture, is messy,
有时候 一个词可能包含很多意思
and sometimes, one can be both.
这是很有可能的
And it's quite possible
他们想要我们提供一些东西
that they're asking us to offer them something,
而不是提供给我们武器
not the other way around.
就好像第一次交易
It's like the first part of a trade.
所以 我们怎样搞明白
So, how do we clarify their intentions
他们究竟是什么意思
beyond those two words?
我会再进去一次
Well, I go back in.
就现在 我们进去搞清楚
Right away, we go back in and we clear this up.
听起来很复杂啊
It's more complicated than that.
这怎么就很复杂了
How is it more complicated than that?
上校 国防部长
Colonel, the Secretary of Defense
要求和你通话
is on the line for you.
在我们弄清楚它的意思之前
We need to sit on this information
这个消息需要保密
till we know what it means,
所以不要告诉我们的敌人
so we aren't sharing it with our enemies.
还有一种情况是
We must consider the idea
我们的观光者想要我们自相残杀
that our visitors are prodding us to fight among ourselves
直到一方取得胜利
until only one faction prevails.
-没有那样的事 -就是这样
- There's no evidence of that. - Sure there is.
多看看历史书吧
Just grab a history book.
英国人和印度人 德国人和卢旺达人
The British with India, the Germans with Rwanda.
他们甚至在匈牙利命名了
They even got a name for it in Hungary.
不只是一个人掌控着这个世界
Yeah. We're a world with no single leader.
他们不可能只和一个国家做交易
It's impossible to deal with just one of us.
而武器这个词
And with the word "Weapon" Now...
-哈尔彭 -在 长官
Halpern. Yes, sir!
暂时没有消息 待命
No confirmation yet. Standing by.
有消息了吗 他们说了什么
Anything? What did they say?
中国和俄罗斯都不在线
China and Russia are off the grid.
他们没和任何人说话
They aren't speaking to anyone.
他们在上次交谈中了解到的内容把他们吓坏了
Whatever they learned in their last session has them spooked.
好的 长官
Yes, sir!
上级要求我们离线
We have orders to do the same.
这些是我们的盟友
These are our allies!
你不能这样
You can't shut us down!
-关闭我们的信号 -快点
- Put us on radio silence. - Do it.
我们收到了来自七脚怪的消息 天啊
We received a message from the hept... Damn it!
我们应该保持沟通
We need to be talking to each other!
你想和他们说话 弄清楚这什么意思
You want to talk to them? Find out what this means.
基地连线已关闭
Base-camp talk is now offline.
所有的传译员和国际联系人
All interpreters and international liaisons,
暂时离开 去向协调人报告
stand down and report to unit coordinators.
我们之前从没有再次对话
We've never re-entered a session before.
露易丝 相信我 我们还有时间
Louise, trust me, okay? We've got time.
我们快成功了对吧
We've just gotta step on it, all right?
使用武器
"Use weapon."
来自外星人的信息
This is the alien message
导致中国政府今天
said to have provoked the Chinese government
让科学家们退出了
to withdraw their scientists from
国际合作任务
the international mission today.
尚将军在声明中说到
In a statement, General Shang said,
中国不再相信外星人了
"China no longer trusts the aliens
他们想要分裂我们
"Who want to divide us.
人类必须相互保护
"Humanity must be protected."
中国请求立即和联合国进行对话
China has asked for immediate talks at the UN.
阿尔法 19
Alpha-one-niner,
我是秃鹰 完毕
this is Condor, over.
阿尔法19 我是秃鹰 请说话 完毕
Alpha-one-niner, this is Condor, come in. Over.
马克思上校 秃鹰未收到回复
Captain Marks, Condor not receiving transmission.
收到请回复
Squelch twice if you hear line.
马克思上校 护送人员被命令
Captain Marks, all escort units
立即停止所有行动
are ordered to cease all activity.
不 不 不 班克斯博士 你不能进去
No, no, no. Dr. Banks, you can't go in there.
我只想问一个问题
I just need to ask one question.
班克斯博士 对话已经结束
Dr. Banks! The session is finished.
你不能 你不能再进去了 里面非常危险
You can't... You can't go back in. It's dangerous.
听着 我们只需要五分钟 不要这么紧张
Look, we just need five minutes. Don't sweat it.
马克思 让他们进去
Marks, let them go.
嘿 艾伯特
Hey, Abbott!
所以 现在是什么 第37次对话
So, what are we calling this? Session 37?
不 是36次 第二部分
Uh, no, 36, part 2.
为什么只有他们俩在里面
Why are they on their own?
我们一直试图联系马克思上校
We've been attempting to hail Captain Marks.
护送小组并未回复 长官
The escort units are not responding, sir.
为什么 安排保护人员
Why not? Send security.
提供武器 到底是什么意思
"Offer weapon, question mark."
你会给我们什么吗
Are you offering us something?
科技 设备 还是方法
Technology, apparatus, method?
看 这是一个不同的词
Yeah, see, this is a different word.
这 这个部分 图案更复杂
This... This segment, it's a lot busier.
提供科技
Give technology
现在
now.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
上尉 十点钟方向
Captain, on your ten.
安保分队已到 长官
Security detail inbound, sir.
倒计时还剩四分钟 我们要坚持到底
T-minus 4 minutes remaining. We need to see this through.
好了 没问题 重新装弹
Okay, this is it. Lock and load.
我们只需要在结束前拖延住他们
We just need to hold them off until it's done.
收到 只进行示警射击和镇压火力
Copy that. Warning shots and suppressive fire only.
全副武装 准备掩护
Load up and get to cover.
保持冷静 我们可以避免人员伤亡
Stay frosty and we can avoid casualties.
艾伯特想让我写在玻璃上
Abbott wants me to write on the barrier.
可以这么做吗
Can you even do that?
不知道
I don't know.
我没法同时用两只手写出来
I can't do it with both hands.
露易丝
Louise...
怎么回事
What is that?
嘿 轻点
Hey! Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
你刚刚脑震荡了 躺回去吧
You suffered a concussion. Just lay back.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
伊恩怎么样
How is Ian?
跟你一样 他没事
Same as you. He's okay.
谁 呃 谁干的
Who, um... Who did this?
啊 几个士兵
Ah, some soldiers.
他们电视看多了
They've been watching too much TV.
什么声音
What is that?
别紧张 放轻松
Take it easy. Take it easy.
这里不再安全了 我们在准备撤离
The site's no longer secure. We're standing by to evacuate.
伊恩在哪
Where's Ian?
大概十分钟前 韦伯把他叫走了
Weber came and got him maybe 10 minutes ago.
直到知道你没事他才离开
He wouldn't leave until he knew you were okay.
你们整个营里的工作人员
Your whole tent is on the clock
都在研究你们刚刚的发现
to figure out whatever it is you were given up there.
这是全部吗
This is all of it?
录像没有被爆炸影响吗
The feed wasn't interrupted by the explosion?
据我所知没有
Not as far as I can see.
你看到了什么
You see something?
哦 还未可知
Oh, I don't know yet.
我需要和露易丝的团队一起研究
I'm gonna need my team to get together with Louise's team.
我需要所有工作人员一起研究
I need everybody working on this.
我们不能离开
We cannot leave.
很高兴你醒了
Glad to see you're awake.
我们需要回到里面 解释我们不是有意这么做的
We need to go back in and explain this wasn't our fault.
-我们不能再进去了 -我们必须进去
- We can't go back inside. - We have to.
刚刚里面发生的是一场袭击
What happened in there was an attack.
我们可以往好处想
We can hope for the best,
但是我收到命令准备反击
but I have orders to prepare for retaliation.
我们可能不得不撤离
We may have to evacuate.
不 这才是错误的举动
No, that's the wrong move.
只要他们不走 我们就必须留下
As long as they stay, we have to stay.
他们不是要走
Well, they're not leaving.
为什么感觉这样更糟
Why does this feel worse?
中国已经准备进攻
China is on the offensive.
他们正在部署军队
They're positioning the military
准备直接把外星飞船轰出大气层
to blow the alien vessel right out of the sky.
若果真如此
And if this happens,
我们就不能坐以待毙
we can't sit around waiting for retaliation.
所以请全部武装
So, get prepared.
空军步兵候命
The Air Force and infantry are standing by.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
今晚 中国将成为首个向外星人宣战
Tonight, China becomes the first world power
的世界强国
to declare war against the aliens.
在联合国
Following the failure of diplomatic efforts
外交努力失败后
at the United Nations,
中国已确定其语言专家将于今夜
China has confirmed that its language experts have tonight
在上海发布最后通牒
delivered an ultimatum at the Shanghai site.
在电视播送声明中
In a televised statement,
尚将军 人民解放军总司令
General Shang, chairman of the People's Liberation Army,
宣称外星人有二十四小时的时间离开中国领区
said the aliens have 24 hours to leave Chinese territory
否则兵戎相见
or face destruction.
同时尚将军主张其他国家领导人
And he urged all other world leaders
同中国联合 统一战线
to unite with China and take a similar stance.
目前飞船着陆点已集结大量武力
With a huge buildup of forces at their landing sites,
巴基斯坦 俄罗斯及苏丹都被认为
Pakistan, Russia and Sudan are thought to be
会追随中国的行动
following China's lead.
肯定不是随机的
It can't be random.
我们得花费数年的时间了
It's going to take us years.
这个词是什么
What's this term here?
妈妈
Mom...
嗯 亲爱的
Hmm? Sweetie...
呃 这说的是什么词
Uh, what's this term for that thing,
一个专业术语
like a... Like a technical term,
当我们交易的时候
where we make a deal,
我们双方都能获益
and we both get something out of it.
妥协
A compromise.
不是
No...
再比如 它是竞争
Like, it's a competition.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm...
最终双方都很高兴
But both sides end up happy.
就像双赢
Like a win-win.
更学术一点
More science-y than that.
如果你想要更科学的说法 打电话给你爸爸
If you want science, call your father.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
我醒了
I'm up.
现在什么时间
What time is it?
现在是你该打开你一直珍藏的美酒的时候
It's time you opened that bottle you've been hiding.
你是不是有什么突破
You cracked something, didn't you?
没错 过来
Yeah. Come here.
看这部分
Take a look at this section.
他好像在说时间
It seems to be talking about time.
他们的时间符号随处可见
Their symbol for time is everywhere.
所以这是什么
So what is this?
一个超光速飞行公式
A formula for faster-than-light travel?
谁说得准
Who can tell?
他们有很多的缺口
There are too many gaps.
没一个完整的
Nothing's complete.
然后我才恍然大悟
Then it dawned on me.
过来这边
Come here.
这里
Right here.
不要只关注存在什么 还要看看空缺的部分
Stop focusing on the ones. Look at the zeroes.
实物数据占多少
How much of this is data?
空缺部分占多少
How much of it is negative space?
所以 我测算了一下
So, I measured it.
0.0833 3循环
0.0833 recurring.
或许你想把它化成一个分数
Perhaps you'd like that as a fraction.
十二分之一
One of twelve.
他们想在这里说的是这是十二个中的一个
What they're saying right here is that this is one of 12.
“我们是一个大整体中的一部分”
"We are part of a larger whole."
或者我们是十二个奖品角逐者其中之一
Or we're one of 12 contestants for the prize.
我为什么要跟他说话
Why do I have to talk to him?
我们都在一起工作
We're all working together.
我们需要和其他地点交流
We need to talk to the other sites,
用他们从七脚怪那里得到的信息帮助他们
help them with what they've gotten from the heptapods.
我们的通讯被中断了
We're blacked out.
中国已经扬言要毁掉他们的外星飞船
China just threatened to destroy their shell.
我们只能靠自己
We're on our own.
但是这也说了所有的部分可以拼凑在一起
But this says that all of the pieces fit together.
我要告诉你没人关心这些
And I'm telling you that no one else cares.
两小时前
Two hours ago,
我们截获了一段俄罗斯秘密通讯的音频
we pulled this audio off a secure channel in Russia.
他们的科研组的一位组员曾试图传播出这条讯息
Someone on the science team there was broadcasting wide.
最后一次会议 外星人声称
In their final session, the aliens said,
“时间紧迫 合众为一”
"There is no time. Many become one."
我担心所有人都开始明火执仗
I fear we have all been given weapons.
如果有人收到这条信息 请
If anyone is receiving this, please...
嗯 我的意思是
Well, I mean,
有很多种方式
there are a lot of ways
可以解释他说的话
you can interpret what he said.
我不需要一个翻译告诉我这是什么意思
I don't need an interpreter to know what this means.
俄罗斯刚刚处决了其中的一个专家
Russia just executed one of their own experts
以防走漏风声
to keep their secret.
“合众为一”的意思可能是
"Many become one" Could just be their way of saying
需要各国通力合作
"Some assembly required."
那为什么只给我们每个国家一部分
Why hand it out to us in pieces?
为什么不直接给我们完整的
Why not just give it all over?
还有什么更好的方式能让我们合作一次
What better way to force us to work together for once?
就算我信你
Even if I did believe you,
你要如何才能让其他国家马首是瞻
how in the world are you gonna get anybody else to play along
贡献出他们的资料
and give up their data?
我们也提供我们的资料
We offer ours in return.
是吗
Yeah?
做一笔交易
A trade?
这叫非零和博弈
It's a non-zero-sum game.
非零和博弈
Non-zero-sum game.
就是这个 对
That's it. Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
有九个着陆地点
Nine of the landing sites have gone
通讯完全中断
total comms blackout.
唯一联络到他们的方式就是长途跋涉
Only way to reach them is to physically drive there
对着边防战士大喊 我们正在进行这种方案
and yell at the border guards, which we're doing,
但是这样太慢了
but it won't be fast enough.
一定有其他方法和他们联络
There must be a way to get the message to them.
我们的盟国有希望 但是这样机会渺茫而且是亡羊补牢
To our allies, maybe, but it's too little too late.
我们现在要做的就是在一国触发全球战争之前
What we need is to get all the other nations online
联系到所有可以通讯的国家
before one starts global war.
但是我们现在无法联系到他们
And there's no way for us to reach them.
好 等一下 有了
Okay, hold on a second. There is!
它现在处于我们的正上方
It's right above us.
对我们来说它才是当务之急
That's problematic for us right now.
国防部认为这个飞船会报复我们
The Pentagon's convinced our shell will retaliate.
我猜他们会命令我们一个小时内撤离
My guess is they'll order us to evacuate within the hour.
听着 他们不是我们的敌人
Look, they're not our enemy.
他们并没有对我们做出攻击性行为
They've made no act of aggression towards us.
也许这就是他们进攻的方式
Maybe this is their way of being aggressive.
这不是问题
That's not the question.
那什么才是问题
What is the question?
现在它已经半英里高
How do we get you back in that room
我们怎么把你们送上去都成问题
when it's half a mile straight up?
我觉得我们在这里的工作已经结束了
I think our work here is done.
现在决定权在上级手里
It's in the hands of our superiors now.
她到底在干什么
What the hell is she doing?
噢 我的天呐 噢 天呐 不
Oh, my God! Oh, God, no!
科斯特洛
Costello...
艾伯特呢
Where's Abbott?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们都很抱歉
We're sorry.
我想要你
I need you to...
我想要你给你们中的其他人发一则信息
I need you to send a message to the other sites.
我不
I don't...
我不懂
I don't understand.
你们来这里的目的是什么
What is your purpose here?
你是如何知晓未来
How can you know the future?
我不
I don't...
我不明白 那个孩子是谁
I don't understand. Who is this child?
这部戏叫做
The show is called
《妈妈爸爸和动物对话》
"Mommy and Daddy talk to Animals."
等一下 不要 等一下
Wait! No! Wait!
-班克斯博士 -露易丝
- Dr. Banks! - Louise!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
-你还好吗 -没事 我没事
- You all right? - Yeah. I'm all right.
发生了什么
What happened?
我正在思考 信息量太大了
I'm trying to figure it out. This is too big.
现在不重要了 我们接到命令立即撤退
Doesn't matter now. We have orders to evacuate.
为什么
Why?
俄罗斯和苏丹已经和中国统一战线
Russia and Sudan are following China.
我不明白
I don't understand.
帮我一下 妈妈
Help me, Mama.
露易丝 哇哦
Louise? Whoa!
妈妈
Mom!
Mama!
抱歉 亲爱的
Sorry, honey.
今天是周几 你知道吗 宝贝
What day is it? Do you know, baby?
星期天
Sunday.
你会像爸爸那样不要我吗
Are you gonna leave me like Daddy did?
哦 汉娜 亲爱的 爸爸没有不要你
Oh, Hannah, honey, your daddy didn't leave you.
这个周末你就可以见到他了
You're gonna see him this weekend.
他不再像以前一样看我了
He doesn't look at me the same way anymore.
是我的错
It's my fault.
我告诉了他一些他还没做好心理准备的话
I told him something that he wasn't ready to hear.
是什么
What?
嗯
Well...
不管你信不信
Believe it or not,
我能预知未来
I know something that's going to happen.
我也无法解释我怎么知道 但我就是知道
I can't explain how I know. I just do.
当我告诉你爸爸的时候 他真的很生气
And when I told your daddy, he got really mad.
她说我做错了选择
And he said I made the wrong choice.
是什么 未来要发生什么
What? What's going to happen?
这和一种十分罕见的疾病有关
It has to do with a really rare disease.
而且它不可阻挡
And it's unstoppable.
就像你一样
Kind of like you are,
像你的泳技和你写的诗
with your swimming and your poetry
以及其他所有你分享给世界的
and all the other amazing things
令人叹为观止的事情
that you share with the world.
我所向披靡吗
I'm unstoppable?
嗯
Yeah.
我扶住你了
I got you.
露易丝 露易丝
Louise? Louise?
我现在才知道为什么我的丈夫离开我
I just realized why my husband left me.
我的丈夫离开了我
My husband left me.
你结婚了吗
You were married?
振作起来 我们离开这里
Come on! Let's get out of here.
妈妈
Mama?
嗯
Yeah?
为什么我叫汉娜
Why's my name Hannah?
请让那些人回来
Get those people back, please.
嗯 你的名字很特别
Well, your name is very special,
因为它是一种回文
because it is a palindrome.
顺读和倒读都一样
It reads the same forward and backward.
好了 兄弟们 给我搭把手
All right, guys, give me a hand here.
-是 长官 -那个放进包里
- Yes, sir. - That goes in the bag.
准备出发
Ready to go!
撤退准备就绪
Evacuation underway.
嘿
Hey...
我们在这里的任务结束了 这个要带走
We're done here! We're taking this with us.
我能看懂
I can read it.
-我知道这是什么 -什么
- I know what it is. - What?
这不是指武器 是说馈赠
It's not a weapon. It's a gift.
武器是他们的语言
The weapon is their language.
他们把它送给了我们 你知道这意味着什么吗
They gave it to us. Do you know what that means?
意味着我们可以学习七脚怪的语言 如果我们活下来的话
So we can learn Heptapod. If we survive.
如果你学会了 当你真正学会的时候
If you learn it, when you really learn it,
你就能够理解他们理解时间的方式
you begin to perceive time the way that they do,
所以你能看到即将发生的事
so you can see what's to come.
但是时间 于他们而言跟我们不同
But time, it isn't the same for them.
时间是非线性的
It's non-linear.
听着 我们已经尽力了 但是还尚不足以
Look, we did our best, but it wasn't enough.
上尉会接你们上去
The captain will load you up.
你们会在五分钟后起飞
You're lifting off in 5 minutes.
伊恩 露易丝 很荣幸能与你们共事
Ian, Louise, it was an honor to work with you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
嘿 上校
Hey, Colonel...
我去问一下我们去哪
I'm gonna find out where we're going.
醒醒 妈妈
Wake up, Mommy!
班克斯博士
Dr. Banks...
很高兴见到你
A pleasure.
尚将军 应该是我与有荣焉
General Shang, the pleasure is mine, really.
贵国总统说
Your president said
很荣幸能在此次庆祝会上款待我
he was honored to host me at the celebration...
的确如此
Yeah.
但是我得坦白 我来此的唯一原因
...but I confess, the only reason why I'm here
就是亲自会见你
is to meet you in person.
我吗 真是不胜荣幸 谢谢
Me? Well, I'm flattered. Thank you.
十八个月前
18 months ago,
你做了一件非比寻常的大事
you did something remarkable,
一件即便是我的上级也做不到的事
something not even my superior has done.
那是什么事
And what's that?
你改变了我的想法
You changed my mind.
你才是此次联合的根源
You're the reason for this unification,
都是因为你联系到了我的私人电话
all because you reached out to me at my private number.
您的私人号码
Your private number?
尚将军 我 我不知道您的私人号码
General, I... I don't know your private number.
现在你知道了
Now you know.
我不强求知道你的大脑如何运作
I do not claim to know how your mind works,
但是我相信对你来说知道号码一定很重要
but I believe it was important for you to see that.
我给你打了电话 是吗
I called you, didn't I?
是的 你给我打了电话
Yes, you did.
露易丝
Louise!
好了可以关闭系统了
All right, let's shut down the system.
长官这里有一个通讯线路正在拨号中国
Sir? There's a sat line here dialing China.
这里 你说“这里”是什么意思
Here? What do you mean "Here"?
拜托 拜托
Come on, come on!
是谁的手机
Whose phone is it?
是你的手机 长官
It's your phone, sir.
立即搜索营地
Search base camp now.
找出是谁在用那部手机
Find out who's using that phone.
盯住那些坐标
And hold on to those coordinates.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
拜托 我要说什么
Come on... What do I say?
我要说什么
What do I say?
拜托
Come on.
我永远都不会忘记你说的话
I will never forget what you said.
你跟我说了我妻子的临终遗言
You told me my wife's dying words.
找到电话信号源了
We found the source of the phone call.
在净化室 原地待命
It's in the clean room. We're waiting for instructions.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
-你在干什么 -改变一个人的想法
- What are you doing? - Changing someone's mind.
-你能帮我争取二十秒吗 -这件事上我们无法争取到时间
- Can you buy me 20 seconds? - We don't have time for this.
不 相信我 帮我争取二十秒
No, trust me. Buy me 20 seconds.
-你相信我吗 -好 我信
- Do you trust me? - Okay. Yeah.
班克斯博士 立即放下手机 否则我们就开枪了
Dr. Banks, drop the phone now or we shoot!
放下手机
Drop it!
对不起
I'm sorry!
你是在犯叛国罪
You are committing an act of treason!
-是 -放下手机
- Yes. - Drop it!
结束了 结束了
It's done. I'm done.
十二地着陆点通讯中断
...blackout from all 12 landing sites
晚上继续为您播报
continues this evening.
稍等 我们刚收到消息
Hold on, we are just hearing...
我刚被告知切到这则
I'm being told we're going to cut this report
爆炸新闻
to tell you breaking news...
中国正在召开紧急新闻发布会
...China has called an emergency press conference...
尚将军
General Shang,
人民解放军总司令
commander in chief of the People's Liberation Army,
在紧急新闻发布会中宣布
has announced in an emergency press conference
中国解除戒备状态
that China is standing down.
所有已接收情报
...all intelligence they've received
将立即与其它着陆点共享
will be shared immediately with the other landing sites.
来自世界各地的科学家都在筛查
Scientists from around the world are sifting through information
接收自英国 日本
received from the UK, Japan,
塞拉利昂和委内瑞拉的信息
Sierra Leone and Venezuela.
他们获取自
...the information they have acquired
其境内着陆点的信息
from both of their landing sites...
都证明十二分其一之谜
Also confirming it to be one of the 12 pieces
正在慢慢拼凑成整体
of this puzzle that is being slowly put together.
所以 汉娜
So, Hannah,
这就是你一生的故事开始的地方
this is where your story begins.
他们离开的那天
The day they departed.
你还好吗
You all right?
尽管知道这次旅程将通往何处
Despite knowing the journey and where it leads,
我还是选择义无反顾地拥抱它
I embrace it.
且安于迎接这次旅程的每一刻
And I welcome every moment of it.
H-a-n-n-a-h
H-a-n-n-a-h.
再倒过来念 H
Now backward. H...
a-n-n-a-h
...a-n-n-a-h!
汉娜
Hannah!
准备好了吗 宝贝
You ready, baby?
嗨
Hi!
别担心 晚安
Don't worry. See you.
爸爸
Daddy!
你还好吗
You okay?
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
噢 你猜是什么 星星的故事
Oh, guess what? Star stuff!
-伊恩 -嗯
- Ian? - Yeah?
如果你能预见自己的一生 从出生到衰亡
If you could see your whole life from start to finish,
你会改变什么吗
would you change things?
或许我会说说我经常感受到的
Maybe I'd say what I feel more often.
我 我也不知道
I... I don't know.
你知道吗 从我开始记事的时候
You know, I've had my head tilted up to the stars
我就经常抬头仰望星空
for as long as I can remember.
你知道最让我惊叹的是什么吗
You know what surprised me the most?
不是海底月是天上月
It wasn't meeting them.
而是眼前人是心上人
It was meeting you.
我都忘了被你抱着的感觉有多好
I forgot how good it felt to be held by you.
你想要一个宝宝吗
You wanna make a baby?
嗯 我想
Yes. Yeah.